Finding Aid for Robert C. Metcalf papers, 1950-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Audio Visual Materials
  - Slides
    - Metcalf Houses, 11 boxes
      - Slide Box 6 (Construction)
        - Job 73-62, Island Park Shelter (Box 12)
        - Job 75-62, Root (Box 12)
        - Job 76-62, Van Boven (Box 12)
        - Job 79-63, BBON Venture (Box 12)
        - Job 80-63, Cage & Smeckert (Box 12)
        - Job 81-63, Heywood (Box 12)
        - Job 87-65, Leabo (Box 12)
        - Job 88-65, Eberbach (Box 12)
        - Job 91-65, Hutt (Box 12)
      - Slide Box 7 (Construction)
        - Job 92-66, K. Siegel (Box 12)
        - Job 95-67, Metcalf Office (Box 12)
        - Job 96-67, Higgins (Box 12)
      - Slide Box 8 (Construction)
        - Job 107-78, Claeys (Box 12)
      - Slide Box 9 (Construction)
        - Job 106-75, Huebner (Box 12)
        - Job 107-78, Claeys (Box 12)
        - Job 113-88, Bartell (Box 12)
        - Job 117-89, Fox/Bockenstedt (Box 12)
        - Job 118-89, Gilbert/Verbrugge (II) (Box 12)
        - Job 126-95, R. Siegel (Box 12)
        - Job 136-99, McCoy/Steele (Box 12)
- Oversized Drawings and Presentation Boards
  (Filed in Metcalf Filing Cabinets by Job Number, from bottom of drawer up. the drawings and presentation boards are also listed n the Project Files series which includes a fuller description of the project and the type and number of drawings for a project. Not all projects have drawings or presentation boards.)
  - Drawings
    - Job Misc. 1950 Brechbuhler (Map-case 1)
    - Job Misc. 1951 Bagent (Map-case 1)
    - Job 1-53, Crane (Map-case 1)
    - Job Misc. 1953 Bull (Map-case 1)
    - Job Misc. 1953 Heller (Map-case 1)
    - Job 2-54, Service (Map-case 1)
      (includes Job 61-60)
    - Job 3-54, Elving (Map-case 1)
    - Job 4-54, Dennison (Map-case 1)
    - Job 5-54, Stockon (Map-case 1)
    - Job 6-54, Williams, B. (Map-case 1)
    - Job Misc. 1954 Warren (Map-case 1)
    - Job 7-55, Forsythe (Map-case 1)
      (includes Job 57-60)
    - Job 8-55, Moore (Map-case 1)
      (includes Job 133-98)
    - Job 9-55, Jones (Map-case 1)
      (includes Job 56-60)
    - Job 10-55, Wollam Restaurant (Map-case 1)
    - Job 11-55, Terwilliger (Map-case 1)
    - Job 12-55, Gamma Phi Beta (Map-case 1)
    - Job 13-55, Hodges (Map-case 1)
    - Job 14-55, King (Map-case 1)
    - Job 15-55, Phillips (Map-case 1)
      (includes Job 110-83)
    - Job 16-55, VW Agency (Map-case 1)
    - Job 17-56, O'Hara (Map-case 1)
    - Job 18-56, Sponseller (Map-case 1)
    - Job 19-56, Paradise (Map-case 1)
    - Job 20-56, Reynolds (Map-case 1)
    - Job 21-56, Gerard (Map-case 1)
      (includes Job 135-99)
    - Job 23-56, Duckek (I) (Map-case 1)
      (includes Job 130-96)
    - Job 24-56, Vaughn (Map-case 1)
    - Job 25-56, ICC Mark VIII House (Map-case 1)
    - Job 26-56, Woods (Map-case 3)
      (includes Job 143-02)
    - Job 27-56, Patterson (Map-case 3)
    - Job 28-57, Magee (Map-case 3)
      (includes drawing for Nordman 1990)
    - Job 29-57, Lyon (Map-case 3)
    - Job 30-57, Riskey (Map-case 3)
    - Job 31-57, Fajans (Map-case 3)
    - Job 32-57, Gottlieb (Map-case 3)
    - Job 33-57, Botch (Map-case 3)
    - Job 34-57, Weid (Map-case 3)
    - Job 35-57, Church of the Good Shepherd United Church of Christ (Map-case 3)
    - Job 36-57, Sahlins (Map-case 3)
    - Job Misc. 1957 Black (Map-case 3)
    - Job 37-58, Harvey (Map-case 3)
    - Job 38-57, Willits (Map-case 3)
    - Job 39-58, Pryor (Map-case 3)
      (includes Job 137-99)
    - Job 40-58, Campbell (Map-case 3)
    - Job 41-58, Titiev (includes Job 55- 60) (Map-case 4)
    - Job 42-58, Les Strang (Map-case 4)
    - Job 43-58, Brown (Map-case 4)
    - Job 44-58, West Park Shelter (Map-case 4)
    - Job 45-59, Dingman (Map-case 4)
    - Job 46-59, Peter (includes Job 112-86) (Map-case 4)
    - Job 47-59, Carr (Map-case 4)
    - Job 48-59, Grimord (includes Jobs 66-61 & 126-95) (Map-case 4)
    - Job 49-59, Busard (Map-case 4)
    - Job 50-59, St. Andrew's United Church of Christ (Map-case 4)
    - Job 51-59, Chen (Map-case 4)
    - Job 52-59, Moyer (Map-case 4)
    - Job 53-59, Wilde (Map-case 4)
    - Job Misc. 1959 Furstenberg (Map-case 4)
    - Job 54-60, Emerick (Map-case 5)
    - Job 55-60, Titiev (Map-case 5)
      (see Job 41-58)
    - Job 56-60, Jones (Map-case 5)
      (see Job 9-55)
    - Job 57-60, Forsythe (Map-case 5)
      (see Job 7-55)
    - Job 58-60, Parry (Map-case 5)
    - Job 59-60, Mulchahey (Map-case 5)
    - Job 60-60, Greenbaum (Map-case 5)
    - Job 61-60, Service (Map-case 5)
      (see Job 2-54)
    - Job 62-60, Tannenbaum (Map-case 5)
    - Job 63-60, Beutler (Map-case 5)
    - Job 64-60, Elliott (Map-case 5)
      (includes Job 132-97)
    - Job 65-60, Case (Map-case 5)
    - Job Misc. 1960 Kleaveland (Map-case 5)
    - Job 66-61, Grimord (Map-case 5)
      (see Job 48-59)
    - Job 67-61, Breed (Map-case 5)
    - Job 68-61, Richard (Map-case 5)
    - Job 69-61, Spencer (Map-case 5)
    - Job 70-61, Ogden (Map-case 5)
    - Job 71-61, Fuller/Hodges Travel Agency (Map-case 5)
    - Job 72-61, Davidson/Sherwin (Map-case 5)
      (designed for Davidson; revised and built for Sherwin)
    - Job Misc. 1961 Hall (Map-case 5)
    - Job Misc. 1961 Likert (Map-case 5)
    - Job Misc. 1961 L. Price (Map-case 6)
    - Job Misc. 1961 Spurr (Map-case 6)
    - Job 73-62, Island Park Shelter (Map-case 6)
    - Job 74-62, Duckek (II) (Map-case 6)
    - Job 75-62, Root (Map-case 6)
    - Job 76-62, Van Boven (Map-case 6)
    - Job 77-62, Churchill (Map-case 6)
    - Job 78-62, Krigbaum (Map-case 6)
    - Job Misc. 1962 Alpha Delta Pi (Werner) (Map-case 6)
    - Job Misc. 1962 Radock (Map-case 6)
    - Job 79-63, BBON Venture Medical Office (Map-case 6)
    - Job 80-63, Cage & Smeckert Dental Office (Map-case 6)
    - Job 81-63, Heywood (Map-case 6)
    - Job 82-63, Laird (I) (Map-case 6)
    - Job 83-64, Swartz (Map-case 6)
    - Job 84-64, Holland (I) (Map-case 7)
      (includes Jobs 109-83, 134-99, & 151-08)
    - Job 85-64, Mann (Map-case 7)
    - Job 86-64, Olds (Map-case 7)
      (includes Job 129-96)
    - Job Misc. 1964 Phi Alpha Kappa (Werner) (Map-case 7)
    - Job Misc. 1964 Warner (Werner) (Map-case 7)
    - Job 87-65, Leabo (Map-case 7)
      (includes Jobs 142-02 & 148-03)
    - Job 88-65, Eberbach (Map-case 7)
    - Job 89-65, Courtland Corp. (Map-case 7)
    - Job 90-65, Miller (Map-case 7)
    - Job Misc. 1965 Bookstein (Map-case 7)
    - Job 91-65, Hutt (Map-case 7)
    - Job 92-66, K. Siegel (Map-case 8)
    - Job 93-66, Swanson (Map-case 8)
    - Job 94-66, Gilbert (I) (Map-case 8)
      (includes Job 141-02)
    - Job Misc. 1966 St. Luke's Lutheran Church (Map-case 8)
    - Job Misc. 1966 Chatas (Werner) (Map-case 8)
    - Job 95-67, Metcalf Office (Map-case 8)
    - Job 96-67, Higgins (Map-case 8)
      (includes Job 114-88)
    - Job Misc. 1967 Lewis (Map-case 8)
    - Job Misc. 1967 Wilkes (Map-case 8)
    - Job 97-68, Towner Medical Office (Map-case 8)
    - Jobs 98-68 & 99-68 Bentley Park Shelter & Bentley Park Bandstand (Map-case 8)
    - Job 100-68, Steiner (Map-case 8)
    - Job 101-69, Nu Sigma Nu (Map-case 8)
    - Job 102-71, Mayerson (Map-case 8)
    - Job 103-71, Ecorse Medical Office (Map-case 8)
    - Job Misc. 1971 Edwards (Map-case 9)
    - Job Misc. 1971 UM Lorch Hall (Map-case 9)
    - Job 105-74, Laird (II) (Map-case 9)
      (includes Job 122-92)
    - Job Misc. 1974 Paul (Map-case 9)
    - Job Misc. 1974 Warner (Werner) (Map-case 9)
    - Job 106-75, Huebner (Map-case 9)
    - Job 107-78, Claeys (Map-case 9)
    - Job 108-80, Watson/Akil (Map-case 9)
      (includes Jobs 123-93, 140-01, & 146-03)
    - Job 109-83, Holland (II) (Map-case 9)
      (see Job 84-64)
    - Job 110-83, Phillips (Map-case 9)
      (see Job 15-55)
    - Job 111-85, Kienholz (Map-case 9)
    - Job 112-86, Stein (Map-case 9)
      (see Job 46-59)
    - Job 113-88, Bartell (Map-case 9)
    - Job 114-88, Higgins (Map-case 9)
      (see Job 96-67)
    - Job 115-88, Ferriell (Map-case 9)
    - Job 117-89, Fox/Bockenstedt (Map-case 9)
    - Job 118-89, Gilbert/Verbrugge (II) (Map-case 9)
    - Job 119-89, Robinson (Map-case 9)
    - Job 120-91, Holland (II) (Map-case 9)
    - Job 121-91, Yao (Map-case 9)
    - Job 122-92, Laird (II) (Map-case 9)
      (see Job 105-74)
    - Job Misc. 1992 Gutstein (Map-case 9)
    - Job Misc. 1992 Jahnke (Map-case 9)
    - Job 123-93, Watson/Akil (Map-case 9)
      (see Job 108-80)
    - Job Misc. 1993 Saladin (Map-case 9)
    - Job 124-94, Hitchman/Hewitt (Map-case 9)
      (see Job 139- 01)
    - Job 125-95, Bareham (Map-case 9)
      (see Job 145-03)
    - Job 126-95, Siegel, R. (Map-case 9)
    - Job 127-95, DeLosh (Map-case 9)
    - Job 128-96, Oak Valley Dental Associates (Map-case 10)
    - Job 129-96, Valenstein (Map-case 10)
      (see Job 86-64)
    - Job 130-96, Waggoner (Map-case 10)
      (see Job 23-56)
    - Job 131-97, Darian (Map-case 10)
    - Job 132-97, Hinman/Young (Map-case 10)
      (see Job 64-60)
    - Job 133-98, Seguino (Map-case 10)
      (see Job 8-55)
    - Job 134-99 Holland (I) (Map-case 10)
    - Job 135-99, Eckstein (Map-case 10)
      (see Job 21-56)
    - Job 136-99, McCoy/Steele (Map-case 10)
    - Job 137-99, Newhouse (Map-case 10)
      (see Job 39-58)
    - Job 138-99, Ann Arbor Airport (Map-case 10)
    - Job Misc. 2000 Owyang (Map-case 10)
    - Job 139-01, Hitchman/Hewitt (Map-case 10)
      (includes Job 124-94)
    - Job 140-01, Watson/Akil (Map-case 10)
    - Job 141-02, Gilbert/Verbrugge (Map-case 10)
      (see Job 94-66)
    - Job 142-02, Grizzle/McCauley (Map-case 10)
      (see Job 87-65)
    - Job 143-02, Cohen (Map-case 10)
      (see Job 26-56)
    - Job 144-02, Hurtado (Map-case 10)
    - Job 145-03, Bareham (Map-case 10)
      (includes Job 125-95)
    - Job 146-03, Watson/Akil (Map-case 10)
    - Job 147-03, Berkowitz (Map-case 10)
    - Job 148-03, Grizzle/McCauley (Map-case 10)
    - Job 149-05, Morshidi/Moazzami (Map-case 10)
    - Job 150-07, Deromedi (Map-case 10)
    - Job 151-08, Holland (I) (Map-case 10)
      (see Job. 84-64)
  - Presentation Boards
    - Job 0-52, Metcalf (Map-case 11)
    - Job 4-54, Dennison (Map-case 11)
    - Job 6-54, B. Williams (Map-case 11)
    - Job Misc. 1954 Morton Arboretum Competition (Map-case 11)
    - Job 11-55, Terwilliger (Map-case 11)
    - Job Misc. 1955 Porcelain Enamel Competition (Map-case 11)
    - Job 24-56, Vaughn (Map-case 11)
    - Job 27-56, Patterson (Map-case 12)
    - Job 28-57, Magee (Map-case 12)
    - Job 31-57, Fajans (Map-case 12)
    - Job 35-57, Church of the Good Shepherd (Map-case 12)
    - Job 42-58, Les Strang (Map-case 13)
    - Job 71-61, Fuller / Hodges Travel Agency (Map-case 13)
    - Job Misc. 1961 Spurr (Map-case 13)
    - Job Misc. 1962 Alpha Delta Pi (Werner (Map-case 13)
    - Job 84-64, Holland (Map-case 13)
      (includes Job 134-99)
    - Job 86-64, Olds (Map-case 14)
    - Job 92-66, Siegel, K. (Map-case 14)
    - Job 94-66, Gilbert/Verbrugge (Map-case 14)
    - Job 95-67, Metcalf Office (Map-case 14)
    - Job 96-67, Higgins (Map-case 14)
    - Job 97-68, Towner Medical Office (Map-case 14)
    - Job 100-68, Steiner (Map-case 14)
    - Job 101-69, Nu Sigma Nu (Map-case 14)
    - Job 106-75, Huebner (Map-case 14)
    - Job 108-80, Watson/Akil (Map-case 14)
    - Job 128-96, Oak Valley Dental (Map-case 14)